

Andrea Gravili

Date of birth: 11/09/2002

Nationality: Italian

Gender: Male

CONTACT

Via Promo 9 25078 Brescia, Italy (Home)

andrea.gravili8@gmail.com

(+39) 3756045429

andreagravili.vercel.app

https://github.com/TitanWasHere (GitHub)

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ andrea-gravili-b1b808254/



ABOUT ME

I have been immersed in the field of Computer Science since a youngage, harboring a keen interest in astronomy and consistently striving forexcellence. This journey has honed my skills as a proficient problem-solverwith a resolute commitment to advancing technological research.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

09/2024 - CURRENT Rome, Italy

Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence and Robotics Sapienza, University of Rome

Website www.uniroma1.it

09/2021 - 16/07/2024 Trento, Italy

Bachelor's degree in computer science University of Trento

Website https://www.unitn.it/

09/2016 - 06/2021 Vobarno (BS), Italy

High School degree in Computer Science ITIS G.Perlasca

Website https://www.istitutoperlasca.edu.it/

WORK EXPERIENCE

08/2024 - 10/2024 Trento, Italy

Robotics Software developer University of Trento

Developing software for an humanoid robot

21/02/2024 - 15/07/2024 Trento, Italy

Robotics engineer intern University of Trento

Working with a humanoid robot, involving tasks such as mapping, planning movement within the environment, and facilitating interactions with users **Skills**: ROS, C++, Python, software for the interaction with an humanoid robot, path planning, problem solving

Goals achieved:

- Robot interaction with people at the Trento Museum of Sciences
- Tested software in University and Museum of Sciences

21/09/2023 - 08/02/2024 Trento, Italy

University tutor University of Trento

Tutoring and support for "Software Engineering" course for 2nd year Computer science students in 2023/2024.

Skills: JS (node.js), react.js, HTML + CSS, the building of a software architecture, Mongo DB, agile, leadership, communication, creativity **Goals achieved**:

- Helped multiple students with their projects with positive feedback
- Better communication and teaching skills

21/06/2023 - 23/06/2024 Trento, Italy

ICT technician University of Trento

I provide technical support for the department's IT activities and assist in resolving computer-related issues while participating in a part-time employment opportunity offered by the university

Skills: Python, Ubuntu, computer architecture, teamwork,communication, Adaptability

01/2021 - 02/2021 Vestone (BS), Italy

Electrician internship Valsir Spa

Working as an assistant electrician, my primary responsibilities included configuring PLC machines and troubleshooting errors in industrial projects aimed at the creation of electrical cabinets

DIGITAL SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C | C++ | Python | PHP | R | Java | PostegreSQL | HTML + CSS (Bootstrap) | Javascript (Vue.js, Node.js) | JSON | Poly ML | Assembly (ARM, RISC-V, Intel x86) | ROS - Robot Operating System | MatLAB

COMPUTER BASICS

Docker | Git | Unix | Microsoft Office Package | GitHub

SOFT SKILLS

Problem solving | Comunication | Creativity | Teamwork

NETWORKING

Wireshark | Kathara | CISCO Packet Tracer

UX / DESIGN

Photoshop | Axure | Figma | Krita

PROJECTS

02/2024 - 07/2024

ARI Thesis

Project for the University of Trento, which deals with a humanoid robot named ARI. My responsibility in this project is to manage the speech and listening node, as well as the calibration and path planning.

Link https://github.com/TitanWasHere/ARI-thesis

02/2023 - 07/2023

TECH - DOWSER

The project for the university course 'Human-Computer Interaction', is a prototype of a potability water detector with a connected application that contains its position and data of the detected water

Link https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1YsaFhWc3lekWEJWNR3tJBMYu7FnEPIeK0

01/01/2023 - 07/01/2023

ISS4U

This is a project carried out for the 'Software Engineering' course. In the following link, you will find the completed application, which was preceded by an agile development technique, including the creation of requirements, components, use-case diagrams, and flowcharts.

Link https://github.com/orgs/SE-T28/

HONOURS AND AWARDS

22/05/2024 venetostars

Winner of the 2024 edition of VenetoStars

Won the 2024 edition of the VenetoStars project, organized by the Veneto region (IT). My team and I were tasked with developing a solution to address a specific issue affecting the UNESCO sites in the Veneto region using space data. We chose to focus on creating a solution to protect and preserve the UNESCO site of the Prosecco Hills of Conegliano and Valdobbiadene. Our project was presented and chosen at the Space Meeting 2024 in Venice.

Project name: Safe-hills

Link https://venetostars.com/#winnerd

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Italiano

Other language(s):

Inglese

Listening B2

Spoken production B2

Reading B2

Spoken interaction B2

Writing B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DRIVING LICENCE

•

Driving Licence: B 26/04/2021 – 11/09/2031

Laive consent to process my data with the purpose of the recruitment process, in accordance to the Degulation of the European
I give consent to process my data with the purpose of the recruitment process, in accordance to the Regulation of the European Parliament 679/2016, regarding the protection of natural persons and free movement of such data